{
    "id": "9cbb73aac2434cb5a7454b3235e747a0",
    "title": "Present continuous tense quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Mother …………………. a cake for me.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is baking",
                "are baking",
                "was baking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………. my breakfast.",
            "description": "When the subject is the first person singular noun 'I', we make the present continuous form by adding 'am' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "eat",
                "am eating",
                "are eating",
                "is eating"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Suma ……………… for us.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "are waiting",
                "am waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie …………………. the flowers in the vase.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is arranging",
                "are arranging",
                "am arranging"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Rahul ………………. for his exams.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am studying",
                "are studying",
                "is studying"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Veena ……………….. the violin.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is playing",
                "am playing",
                "are playing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister ………………. her homework.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are doing",
                "am doing",
                "is doing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The girls ……………….. their dialogues.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are rehearsing",
                "is rehearsing",
                "am rehearsing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The cat ……………….. the mouse.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "am chasing",
                "is chasing",
                "are chasing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy ………………. water from the pond.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is fetching",
                "am fetching",
                "are fetching"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The students .............................. their lessons.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is learning",
                "am learning",
                "are learning"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The children ................................ kites.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is flying",
                "am flying",
                "are flying"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}